Family vacations can be tricky.
Wizards of Waverly Place: The Movie is a family, tv movie,
adventure film directed by Lev L. Spiro.
A young wizard accidentally conjures a spell that puts her family in jeopardy.
Alex Russo, played by Selena Gomez.
Justin Russo, played by David Henrie.
Max Russo, played by Jake T. Austin.
Theresa Russo, played by Maria Canals-Barrera.
Jerry Russo, played by David DeLuise.
Archie, played by Steve Valentine.
Wizards of Waverly Place: The Movie is a 2009 American fantasy comedy drama television
film based on the Disney Channel Original Series Wizards of Waverly Place.
It was directed by Lev L.
Spiro and filmed primarily in San Juan, Puerto Rico in February and March 2009.
The full cast of the series starred in the film, although Jennifer
Stone only had a small role at the beginning of the film.
The film focuses on Alex Russo having to reverse a wish she made that her parents
never met after being grounded during a trip to the Caribbean.
The film premiered on August 28, 2009, on the
Disney Channel in the United States.
It received 11.4 million viewers at its premiere, making it the second-most-viewed Disney
Channel Original Movie premiere at that time, after High School Musical 2.
It was also cable's No.
1 scripted telecast of 2009 in total viewers.
It premiered in the UK and Ireland on October 23,
2009, as part of Wiz-Tober 2009.
It was released on DVD on December 15, 2009, as an Extended Edition.
The film won the 2010 Primetime Emmy Award for Outstanding Children's Program.
The film explores themes of island, sibling relationship,
magic, foreign language, family vacation.
The tone is lighthearted and emotional.